carsireland.ie 2004-10-15

# Cars Ireland

| 

## CARS IRELAND PRIVACY AND CONFIDENTIALITY STATEMENT

### DATA PROTECTION ACT

Cars Ireland will only hold information in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act 1998, and will adhere to any other relevant future legislation in this area. Under this legislation, members can obtain a copy of all information, which Cars Ireland has on its databases in relation to them. Members wishing to obtain such information should contact [info@carsireland.ie](mailto:info@carsireland.ie). 

### Controllers of Personal Information

Any personal information provided or to be gathered by Cars Ireland is controlled primarily by Cars Ireland, 7 Mount Argus Way, Harolds Cross, Dublin 6W. Cars Ireland adheres to the European Directive on data protection. 

### Does Car Ireland Share the Information It Receives?

We share customer information only as described below: 

  * **Agents:** we employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. Further, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice and as permitted by the Data Protection Act. 
  * **Promotional offers:** sometimes we send offers to selected groups of Cars Ireland users on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we do not give them your name or address. If you do not want to receive such offers, please send a blank email to [remove@carsireland.ie](mailto:remove@carsireland.ie). 
  * **Business transfers:** In the unlikely event that Cars Ireland or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets. 
**Protection of Cars Ireland and others:** we release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law, to enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements or to protect the rights, property or safety of Cars Ireland, our users or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in a way that is contrary to the commitments made in this Privacy Notice. 
  * **With your consent:** other than as set out above, you will receive notice when information about you might go to third parties and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information unless you expressly requested information e.g. to order a brochure on a car from a distributor. 

### What Choices Do I Have?

If you do not want to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please send a blank email to [remove@carsireland.ie](mailto:remove@carsireland.ie). 

### Conditions of Use, Notices and Revisions

This notice is governed by the laws of Ireland. If you have any concern about privacy at Cars Ireland, please send a thorough description to info@carsireland.ie and we will try to resolve it. 

Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Notice will change also. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check our website frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We stand behind the promises we make, however, and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers. 

### Automatic Information

Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, login, e-mail address, password, computer and connection information such as browser type and version, your operating system and platform, purchase history, which we sometimes aggregate with similar information from other customers to create features the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), through and from our website (including date and time), cookie number and products/vehicles/editorial you viewed or searched for. 

### Use of information

Cars Ireland only holds and uses personal information to provide additional service to our users. To this end, information collected on members will only be made available to appropriate companies retailers. 

### Public forum

This site may from time to time make available, chat rooms, forums, message boards, and similar media for members to express views and ideas. It should be noted that information posted to these areas becomes public information and Cars Ireland advise that no personal details should be disclosed in such areas. 

### Questions and answers

We have tried to anticipate any queries you may have in relation to the area of privacy and confidentiality. If this statement fails to address any issue you may have in this are, please contact the helpdesk at [help@carsireland.ie](mailto:help@carsireland.ie) for further details. 

### Feedback

If you want to express a view direct to Cars Ireland, then please email us at [info@carsireland.ie](mailto:info@carsireland.ie). 

|
